<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on SummerCamp 2022 - SRE France</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on SummerCamp 2022 - SRE France</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sre-summercamp.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/arthur_busser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/arthur_busser/</guid><description>Arthur is an SRE @ Padok where he builds cloud infrastructure. He maintains a couple open source projects and believes in keeping things simple.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/benoit_goujon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/benoit_goujon/</guid><description>Benoit est data engineer chez Artefact. Il aide les entreprises à construire leur prochaine plateforme de données. C&amp;rsquo;est lors de ces missions qu&amp;rsquo;il rencontre des problématiques de scalabilité, de sécurité et résilience et c&amp;rsquo;est ce qui l&amp;rsquo;amène à s&amp;rsquo;intéresser de plus près aux pratiques SRE.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/guilhem_lettron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/guilhem_lettron/</guid><description>SRE indépendant / Partisan du DevOps, Podcasteur @DevObs_Podcast</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/mathieu_corbin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/mathieu_corbin/</guid><description>Je suis Staff SRE chez Qonto où je travaille sur tout type de problématiques.
Site web</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/sacha_bernheim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/speakers/sacha_bernheim/</guid><description>Sacha is a SRE @Padok. He maintains and improves state of the art Kubernetes infrastructure on a daily basis while minimizing their complexity. &amp;lt;insert something funny here&amp;gt; He loves explaining simply complex subject and sharing his work with the community through open source contributions.</description></item><item><title>1ère journée</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/round_table_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/round_table_1/</guid><description>Venez échanger de manière plus calme et détendue avec les speakers de cette première journée dans une table ronde animée par le podcast DevObs.</description></item><item><title>2ème journée</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/round_table_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/round_table_2/</guid><description>Venez échanger de manière plus calme et détendue avec les speakers de cette deuxième journée dans une table ronde animée par le podcast DevObs.</description></item><item><title>Accueil, Thé, Café et Croissants</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__open/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__open/</guid><description>Accueil, Thé, Café et Croissants</description></item><item><title>Call For Paper</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/cfp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/cfp/</guid><description>SRE Summer Camp will take place on September 3-4, 2022 at La Dynamo Chambéry.
While waiting for the D-day do not hesitate to propose your talk at CFP. It is now open until August 21, 2022.
Categories Principes and best practices SRE On-call Monitoring Incident management Cloud Native tools IaC (Infrastructure as Code) Experience feedback WTF and other : if your talk does not fit in any of the previous categories.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>SRE France Summer Camp is an event organised for all to offer an inclusive experiment without harassment (sexual, physical, origins, beliefs, etc.)
Harassment in any forms is prohibited, in the society and in the event itself (including slide decks and talks). People that do not respect this could be sanctionned and banned from the event.
At any time, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to contact: srefranceasso+summercamp@gmail.com if you witnessed suspiscious activity or if you lived a violent situation.</description></item><item><title>De SRE à DRE, comment les pratiques SRE influencent le monde de la data</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/de-sre-a-dre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/de-sre-a-dre/</guid><description>Dans ce talk, nous verrons comment les data engineers s&amp;rsquo;inspirent de leurs homologues SRE pour construire des infrastructures data plus résilientes.
En effet, le monde de la data devenant de plus en plus mature, les problématiques liées à la gestion d&amp;rsquo;applications en production apparaissent. Les data engineers ne sont pas forcément formés et outillés pour les adresser. C&amp;rsquo;est donc du côté des SRE qu&amp;rsquo;ils peuvent se pencher pour trouver de bonnes idées.</description></item><item><title>Déjeuner</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__lunch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__lunch/</guid><description>Bon appétit</description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/faq/</guid><description>SRE France Summer Camp - what is it? It&amp;rsquo;s a two days event mixing talks and outdoor activies to encourage discussions around the topics seen during the conferences. SRE France is an association that organizes meetups and events around DevOps and SRE topics in France.
Where and when? 3rd and 4th of September 2022 at La Dynamo Chambéry (24 Avenue Daniel Rops, 73000 Chambéry).
How to come? Directly by train from Paris or from Lyon, Grenoble or Annecy.</description></item><item><title>Hiking and Board games</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/activity_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/activity_2/</guid><description>There are 2 available activities:
Hiking across the mountains near Chambéry during 2 or 3 hours Several board games to play with everyone</description></item><item><title>Hiking and Climbing</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/activity_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/activity_1/</guid><description>There are 2 available activities:
Hiking across the mountains near Chambéry during 2 or 3 hours A 3 hours climbing session, it will be outdoor or indoor depending on the weather</description></item><item><title>Keynote des organisateurs</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/keynote_open/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/keynote_open/</guid><description>Bienvenues au SRE Summer Camp 2022 Présentation de la conférence par les organisateurs.</description></item><item><title>Kube Careers</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_careers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_careers/</guid><description>Kube Careers Kube Careers is the job board for Kubernetes focused jobs. Here is what you can expect:
Clear salary ranges. So you know when it&amp;rsquo;s worth applying. Only Kubernetes jobs. Have you ever found those pesky job ads that mention Kubernetes, but you end up working on 100% legacy codebase. Well, we don&amp;rsquo;t list those. Honest job ads. For every job, we ask ourselves, &amp;ldquo;is this something I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to apply to?</description></item><item><title>Kube Events</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_events/</guid><description>Kube Events When is the next Kube-related conference? (apart from KubeCon, of course) Did you know that there was a meetup last week that covered Kubernetes node scaling with Karpenter? When is the next in-person conference? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if there was a website where you could see all upcoming Kubernetes events?
Enter Kube Events.
Kube Events has a simple goal: surfacing the best upcoming Kubernetes events around you and online.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes @ no-scale</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/kubernetes-at-no-scale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/kubernetes-at-no-scale/</guid><description>Kubernetes est souvent présenté comme l&amp;rsquo;outil de gestion pour les grandes entreprises, les grands déploiements. Dans ce talk, établie sur une expérience réelle @themecloud.io, nous verrons comment Kubernetes profite également aux petits projets, aux (toutes) petites équipes avec pourtant beaucoup de &amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>La Dynamo Chambéry</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/soutien/la_dynamo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/soutien/la_dynamo/</guid><description>Installée à l’entrée du Quartier prioritaire Politique de la Ville des Hauts de Chambéry et ouvert au printemps 2018, la Dynamo, établissement municipal de la ville de Chambéry, est aujourd’hui un lieu d’expérimentation et d’innovation sociale qui abrite un écosystème d’acteurs, de services et d’activités dédiés à la jeunesse, au numérique, à l’insertion professionnelle, aux cultures urbaines, à l’innovation sociale et aux relations internationales.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/lightning_talks_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/lightning_talks_1/</guid><description>Une série de présentations spontanées de moins de 5 minutes avec de slides ou pas.
Cycle de release de Flatcar par Mathieu Tortuyaux MEPIE: un framework DevOps est possible ! par Guilhem Lettron Refactorisation Terraform par Arthur Busser Mirabelle par Mathieu Corbin</description></item><item><title>Mathieu Tortuyaux</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/mathieu_tortuyaux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/mathieu_tortuyaux/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Maximizing development experience by minimizing cost: A dream come true with ArgoCD and Istio's overlays</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/maximizing-development-experience-by-minimizing-cost-a-dream-come-true-with-argocd-and-istios-overlays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/maximizing-development-experience-by-minimizing-cost-a-dream-come-true-with-argocd-and-istios-overlays/</guid><description>Companies struggle to provide an adequate development environment: rapid growth leads to a focus on production environments, while the developer teams scale at least as much the company and little to no effort is put on their daily work experience. An easy solution is to deploy a full application ecosystem for each developer, but it costs too much, so companies share those environments between developers. They should not.
As an ex-developer, I am convinced that each and every developer should be able to test new features without risking impacting other developers.</description></item><item><title>Pablo Seminario</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/pablo_seminario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/pablo_seminario/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Party time...</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__party/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__party/</guid><description>🎉 Party time</description></item><item><title>Pause</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__pause/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/__pause/</guid><description>Pause</description></item><item><title>Prénom Nom</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/prenom_nom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/prenom_nom/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Resilience</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/gold/resilience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/gold/resilience/</guid><description>The platform that supports cancer patients on their path to resilience.
The problem we want to solve
Cancer patients do not benefit from any personalised follow-up of their treatments, even though they are fighting a double battle: against the disease, but also against the side effects.
Our mission
Universalise medical excellence in oncology to enable people to live better and longer.
Our vision
In the face of inequalities in access to medicine, which are particularly tangible for cancer patients, technology must be placed at the service of oncology in order to improve access to knowledge and the effectiveness of therapies.</description></item><item><title>Risques, erreurs et expertise</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/risques-erreurs-et-expertise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/risques-erreurs-et-expertise/</guid><description>Bien que largement délaissé, la gestion du risque est pourtant à la base du métier de SRE. Dans ce talk, explorons le lien étroit entre risques, erreurs et innovation.
Mais, attention, car la route est semée de pièges et d&amp;rsquo;embuches. Et ce qui fait la différence : l&amp;rsquo;expertise.</description></item><item><title>Rym</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/rym/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/team/volunteers/rym/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Secrets, race conditions, and statelessness</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/secrets-race-conditions-and-statelessness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/secrets-race-conditions-and-statelessness/</guid><description>Race conditions during service upgrades are the worst. Particularly when a service and its configuration are both updated at the same time, asynchronously, and something goes subtly wrong. In some cases, we end up with inconsistency between multiples instances of the same stateless service.
But wait, isn&amp;rsquo;t the whole point of a stateless service that all instances are identical in every way? Well, yes. But it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make your services a tiny bit stateful without realising it, and a lot of us have been doing just that.</description></item><item><title>SRE France</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/communautes/sre_france/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/communautes/sre_france/</guid><description>Find SRE France on sre-france.github.io</description></item><item><title>Une CLI pour les gouverner toutes</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/une-cli-pour-les-gouverner-toutes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/sessions/une-cli-pour-les-gouverner-toutes/</guid><description>L&amp;rsquo;écriture de scripts fait partie intégrante de nos métiers. On retrouve pourtant très souvent les mêmes problèmes en entreprise sur comment ces scripts sont écrits et distribués, comme par exemple:
Des scripts souvent très spécifiques et donc peu réutilisables Des scripts disséminés dans de multiples dépôts git, voir non versionnés ou même non partagés Une qualité globale assez faible sur le code de ces scripts, notamment à cause de l&amp;rsquo;utilisation de langages comme bash Je décrirai dans ce lightning talk comment résoudre ces problématiques et expliquerai comment et pourquoi nous avons développé qontoctl chez Qonto.</description></item></channel></rss>