<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Partners on SummerCamp 2022 - SRE France</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/</link><description>Recent content in Partners on SummerCamp 2022 - SRE France</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kube Careers</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_careers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_careers/</guid><description>Kube Careers Kube Careers is the job board for Kubernetes focused jobs. Here is what you can expect:
Clear salary ranges. So you know when it&amp;rsquo;s worth applying. Only Kubernetes jobs. Have you ever found those pesky job ads that mention Kubernetes, but you end up working on 100% legacy codebase. Well, we don&amp;rsquo;t list those. Honest job ads. For every job, we ask ourselves, &amp;ldquo;is this something I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to apply to?</description></item><item><title>Kube Events</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_events/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/media/kube_events/</guid><description>Kube Events When is the next Kube-related conference? (apart from KubeCon, of course) Did you know that there was a meetup last week that covered Kubernetes node scaling with Karpenter? When is the next in-person conference? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if there was a website where you could see all upcoming Kubernetes events?
Enter Kube Events.
Kube Events has a simple goal: surfacing the best upcoming Kubernetes events around you and online.</description></item><item><title>La Dynamo Chambéry</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/soutien/la_dynamo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/soutien/la_dynamo/</guid><description>Installée à l’entrée du Quartier prioritaire Politique de la Ville des Hauts de Chambéry et ouvert au printemps 2018, la Dynamo, établissement municipal de la ville de Chambéry, est aujourd’hui un lieu d’expérimentation et d’innovation sociale qui abrite un écosystème d’acteurs, de services et d’activités dédiés à la jeunesse, au numérique, à l’insertion professionnelle, aux cultures urbaines, à l’innovation sociale et aux relations internationales.</description></item><item><title>Resilience</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/gold/resilience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/gold/resilience/</guid><description>The platform that supports cancer patients on their path to resilience.
The problem we want to solve
Cancer patients do not benefit from any personalised follow-up of their treatments, even though they are fighting a double battle: against the disease, but also against the side effects.
Our mission
Universalise medical excellence in oncology to enable people to live better and longer.
Our vision
In the face of inequalities in access to medicine, which are particularly tangible for cancer patients, technology must be placed at the service of oncology in order to improve access to knowledge and the effectiveness of therapies.</description></item><item><title>SRE France</title><link>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/communautes/sre_france/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sre-summercamp.github.io/partners/communautes/sre_france/</guid><description>Find SRE France on sre-france.github.io</description></item></channel></rss>